Her voice would not be silenced.
The United States vs. Billie Holiday is a music, drama,
history film directed by Lee Daniels.
Billie Holiday spent much of her career being adored by fans.
In the 1940s, the government targeted Holiday in a growing effort to racialize the war on drugs,
ultimately aiming to stop her from singing her controversial ballad, "Strange Fruit."
Billie Holiday, played by Andra Day.
Jimmy Fletcher, played by Trevante Rhodes.
Harry Anslinger, played by Garrett Hedlund.
Reginald Lord Devine, played by Leslie Jordan.
Miss Freddy, played by Miss Lawrence.
Mrs. Fletcher, played by Adriane Lenox.
The United States vs.
Billie Holiday is a 2021 American biographical drama
film about singer Billie Holiday.
Directed by Lee Daniels, the film stars Andra Day in the title role, along with Trevante Rhodes, Garrett Hedlund, Leslie Jordan (in his final film
appearance), Miss Lawrence, Adriane Lenox, Natasha Lyonne, Rob Morgan, Da'Vine Joy Randolph, Evan Ross, and Tyler James Williams.
The film was partly based on the book Chasing the Scream: The First
and Last Days of the War on Drugs by Johann Hari.
Initially set to be released theatrically in the United States by Paramount Pictures, the film was sold to
Hulu in December 2020 and digitally released in the United States on February 26, 2021.
The United States vs.
Billie Holiday received mixed reviews from critics; while Day's performance was
praised, the direction and screenplay were criticized as unfocused.
For her performance, Day was nominated for the Academy Award for Best Actress and
won the Golden Globe Award for Best Actress – Motion Picture Drama.
The film was also nominated for the Golden Globe Award for Best Original Song ("Tigress and Tweed") and the soundtrack won the
Grammy Award for Best Compilation Soundtrack for Visual Media, for Andra Day, Salaam Remi, and Lynn Fainchtein.
The film explores themes of war on drugs, new orleans, louisiana, jazz
singer or musician, ban from profession, biography.
The tone is emotional.